<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>summernalie.github.io/thethingis/</title>
   
   <link>http://www.samanalie.com/thethingis/</link>
   <description>Thoughts on Movies, Books and TV</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> Samanalie Dias Jayasinha</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>The thing is... Wonder Woman is What We've Been Waiting For</title>
	  <link>/thethingis//wonder-woman-review</link>
	  <author>Samanalie Dias Jayasinha</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-06-02T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/thethingis//wonder-woman-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	             <section id="intro">
            <div class="overlay darken"></div>
            <img src="assets/img/ww/ww-sands.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Wonder Woman banner" />
            
            <div class="logo-contain">
                <div class="wr-logo logo-left" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.5s">
                    <img src="assets/img/ww/logo-left.png"  alt="Wonder Woman logo"/>
                </div>
                <div class="wr-logo logo-right" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 0.5s">
                    <img src="assets/img/ww/logo-right.png" alt="Wonder Woman logo"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            
            
            <h1>
               <i id="shadow">Wonder Woman</i> <i id="upper">Wonder Woman</i> <span>Movie Review</span>
            </h1>
            
            
            
        </section>
        <section id="sec1">
            <div class="container" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.5s">
                <p>
                    As I sat in the theatre with the lights dimmed and the all new DC logo forming on the screen in front of me, the sense of sheer anticipation I was feeling is hard to describe in words. Somehow, this movie meant something more than just a movie to me. Somehow, I found myself personally invested in this, and wanting more than anything to see a movie that could live up to all my hype and aspirations for it. </p>
                <p>And it did.</p>
            </div>
                
        </section>
        <section id="points" class="">
            <div class="point" id="point1">
                <div class="overlay"></div>
                
                <div class="container">
                    <div class="row">
                        <div class="col-sm-12">
                            <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">A movie that succeeds</h3>
                            
                            <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">Wonder Woman is not just a good superhero movie; it's a great movie, period. In fact, it doesn't really feel like a superhero movie at all. It starts off as a telling of ancient mythology and fantasy, and leads into what can only be described as a war film. And war seems to be the word heard most throughout the film, and yet at every turn, we the audience know that war is not the hero of this movie. Peace, Justice and Love are the final victors of the day, and the message is carried upon the shoulders of what is clearly the best superhero to come out of the DC Extended Universe yet.</p>
                            <div class="row">
                                <div class="col-sm-12">
                                    <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">I could go on and on about the cinematography, the nuanced performances, the thrilling action and the overall cohesiveness of the story as a whole. These are all executed brilliantly in the movie, no doubt. And even if all you're looking for is an entertaining and engaging film, or even just a ton of eye-candy, you'll enjoy Wonder Woman.</p>
                                    <img src="assets/img/ww/action.jpg" class="img-responsive" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s" alt="Wonder Woman in Action"/>
                                    <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">But as a woman, watching a powerful female heroine conquering the battlefield, leading the charge, and standing for what's right; it was exhilarating. I never realized how much I wanted to feel represented in the films I watch, until I saw it done right. And Wonder Woman does it right.</p>
                                </div>
                            </div>

                            
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div class="point  container-fluid" id="point2">
                <div class="overlay"></div>
                    <div class="container">
                        
                         <div class="row">
                             <div class="col-sm-6">
                                 <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">Undeniably Wonder Woman</h3>
                                  <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">If there was a shred of doubt left about Gal Gadot's ability to inhabit this role, it's long gone now. She is Wonder Woman. Sweetly innocent, extremely powerful and carrying herself with elegance and grace, Gal is nothing short of inspiring to watch. Chris Pine delivers my favourite performance of his to date, and his undeniable chemistry with Gal lays the foundation for some of the most moving moments of the film.
                            </p>
                             </div>
                             <div class="col-sm-6">
                                 <img src="assets/img/ww/galchris.jpg" class="img-responsive" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s" alt="Gal Gadot and Chris Pine"/>
                             </div>
                        </div>
                       
                       
                    </div>
            </div>
            
            
            <div class="point" id="point3">
                <div class="overlay"></div>
                <div class="container">
                    <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">Masterful Storytelling</h3>
                    <div class="row">
                        <div class="col-sm-6">
                            <img src="assets/img/ww/directing.jpg" class="img-responsive" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s" alt="Patty Jenkins and Gal Gadot"/>
                        </div>
                        <div class="col-sm-6">
                            <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.3s">
                                Patty Jenkins has achieved something monumental with this movie. Being the first female director to be at the helm of a film of this scale, she has undoubtedly succeeded in crafting a great piece of film-making. This will be a historic mark for female directors, and will hopefully open up more opportunities for us to see a female voice represented not just in small indie films, but also in big summer blockbusters.
                            </p>
                        </div>
                        
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            
            <div class="point container-fluid" id="point4">
                <div class="overlay"></div>
                    <div class="container">
                        <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">Crossing Genres</h3>

                       
                        <div class="">
                        <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.5s">
                            The movie blends together a myriad of genres and tones, starting us off in realms of greek mythology on the island of Themyscira, and transitioning to the complete opposite side of the spectrum, in the harsh filth of world war one. It's a vivid contrast in atmosphere, but the movie handles it well. It perfectly combines epic action, with poignant emotional moments, dashes of sincere humor that doesn't feel forced, and compelling character growth. I was half-expecting them to avoid romance in the movie, merely as a way to subvert any clichés of the genre, but even that aspect is handled tastefully and feels completely believable and honest in the context of the story.</p>
                    </div>
                        </div>
            </div>
            
            
                    
                    <div class="point clearfix" id="point6">
                        <div class="container">
                            <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">The right balance of Humour and Heart</h3>
                            <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.3s">A note on the humour; superhero movies as of late seem to be trying their hardest to make us laugh. And if you've been paying attention, you'd have noticed that it's starting to beat the audience over the head with it. DC as a whole seems to have avoided that approach with DCEU, but when Wonder Woman was touted as being lighter and more humourous movie, I had trepidations that it would have been too "marvel-ized". But as a credit to the screenwriters, the movie's laughs feel completely natural in the narrative, and the comedy weaves itself seamlessly into the story.
</p>
                           
                        </div>
                        
                    </div>
            
                
        </section>
            <section id="summary">
                <div class="overlay"></div>
            <div class="point container">
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-sm-12" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                        <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">Lasting impact</h3>
                        <p>
                            As the credits rolled, and the closing soundtrack soared, I had to sit in my seat for awhile before I was ready to leave the theatre. I felt moved, hopeful and optimistic. I felt inspired and uplifted. I wanted to immediately watch the film all over again. And funnily enough, at that moment, I wished I had a daughter whom I could show this film to, and tell her that superheroes can look like her. I truly think this movie will have a lasting resonance and impact in years to come, and while it is a great film, it's also an important film for a generation of movie-goers. The thing is, Wonder Woman is what we've been waiting for and so much more.

                        </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                
            </div>
                
        </section>
        

  

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The thing is... Wonder Woman is Worth Getting Excited For</title>
	  <link>/thethingis//wonder-woman-anticipation</link>
	  <author>Samanalie Dias Jayasinha</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-05-04T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/thethingis//wonder-woman-anticipation</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	             <section id="intro">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <img src="assets/img/ww/banner.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Wonder Woman banner" />
            
            <h1 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s">
               <i id="shadow">Wonder Woman</i> <i id="upper">Wonder Woman</i> <span>Is Worth Getting Excited For</span>
            </h1>
            
            <div class="logo-contain">
                <div class="wr-logo logo-left" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 2s">
                    <img src="assets/img/ww/logo-left.png"  alt="Wonder Woman logo"/>
                </div>
                <div class="wr-logo logo-right" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 2s">
                    <img src="assets/img/ww/logo-right.png" alt="Wonder Woman logo"/>
                </div>
            </div>
            
        </section>
        <section id="sec1">
            <div class="container" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.5s">
                <p>
                    With every glimpse into the upcoming Wonder Woman movie, there's a collective thrum of anticipation for what's to come. Could this finally be a female superhero movie that could supersede that classification? Could it just be a great superhero movie, or better yet, could it just be a great movie? I think it will be. </p>
            </div>
                
        </section>
        <section id="points" class="">
            <div class="point" id="point1">
                <div class="overlay"></div>
                <h2 class="subheading text-center" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">And here's why:</h2>
                <div class="container">
                    <div class="row">
                        <div class="col-sm-12">
                            <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">Timely and Timeless Character Design</h3>
                            <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s">Zack Snyder's unique vision for the DCEU has included incredible character designs for our favourite heroes. He's succeeded in making them stand above the world around them, Gods among men, and Wonder Woman more so than others.</p>
                            <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.5s">Her first-ever character poster was met with some scepticism due to the dull tones and monochromatic color-correction. But once we saw it in action in Batman v Superman, all doubts were tabled. Even though her armour was a lot more muted in comparison to the comics, it made sense for the narrative context in terms of it being centuries old. When the posters for the Wonder Woman movie were released, we got an even better look at that iconic costume in it's true glory. </p>
                            <div class="row">
                                <div class="col-sm-6">
                                    <img src="assets/img/ww/bvs-ww.jpg" class="img-responsive pull-right" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.5s" alt="Wonder Woman poster"/>
                                </div>
                                <div class="col-sm-6">
                                    <img src="assets/img/ww/ww-bright.jpg" class="img-responsive pull-left" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 0.5s" alt="Wonder Woman poster"/>
                                </div>
                                <div class="col-sm-12">
                                    <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">They embraced the vibrant hues, and showed off the deep reds and blues that harken back to her original comic look, without being gaudy or overdone. The overall design of her costume is based around greek armour, and expertly walks that fine-line between femininity and ferocity. And while it is a substantially revealing outfit as a whole, somehow she doesn't look overly-sexualized as she has often been in the comics.
                                    </p>
                                </div>
                            </div>

                            <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s"> Giving us a version of Wonder Woman that stays true to her comic roots, while updating her for our time, and still keeps her looking timeless, is a feat to be applauded. Wonder Woman's character design could have easily veered into gratuitous or silly territory, but it ends up being undoubtedly powerful and undoubtedly beautiful.
                            </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <div class="point  container-fluid" id="point2">
                <div class="overlay"></div>
                    <div class="wr-gal clearfix">
                        <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">Gal Gadot</h3>
                         <img src="assets/img/ww/Gal.jpg" id="gal" class="img-responsive"  data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 0.2s" alt="Gal Gadot Comic Con"/>
                        <div id="gal1"  data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.2s">
                            <p>When Gal Gadot was cast as the world's most famous female superhero, the internet had a collective meltdown. One criticism was due to her being too much of a new-comer to carry such a weighty role. But annoyingly, the loudest criticism was around her physical appearance. Fans argued that she wasn't, as she so sweetly put it, "big-hearted" enough for the role of Wonder Woman, who was generally portrayed as a buxom female with her costume barely managing to contain her curves. Those arguments have all since been quelled, after Gal managed to steal the show from two of the greatest superheroes in history in their own movie no less, even with very little screen-time.</p> 
                         </div>
                        <div id="gal2"  data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.2s">
                            <!--<div class="clearfix">
                                <img src="assets/img/ww/glasses.gif" class="pull-left img-responsive"  alt="Wonder Woman Gal Gadot"/>
                                <img src="assets/img/ww/dance.gif" class="pull-left img-responsive"  alt="Wonder Woman Gal Gadot"/>
                            </div>-->
                            <p>Her embodiment of the character both on and off screen has been apparent. She exudes charisma and sophistication, and yet she's not afraid to be goofy and there's just something so entirely relatable about her. More than anything, she's proved that regardless of your physicality or others' expectations of you, how you carry yourself as an individual will be what matters in the end. She's brought a whole new dimension to a 75 year-old character, and for that, Gal, we salute you!</p>
                       </div>
                       
                    </div>
            </div>
            
            
            <div class="point" id="point3">
                <div class="overlay"></div>
                <div class="container">
                    <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">Patty Jenkins</h3>
                    <div class="row">
                        <div class="col-sm-3"> <img src="assets/img/ww/jenkins.jpg" class="img-responsive" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s"  alt="Patty Jenkins"/></div>
                        <div class="col-sm-6">
                            <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.3s">
                                Having a female director be at the helm of the first live-action Wonder Woman movie is an important place to start. To have a director with the talent and gravitas that Patty Jenkins brings to the table, is an even bigger asset to the movie. Not only is she an award-winning film-maker, but hearing her talk about the project with such affection and warmth, makes it evident that she is as ardent a fan as any. A perfect blend of talent and passion is exactly what this movie needs to go beyond being good, and be great.
                            </p>
                        </div>
                        <div class="col-sm-3"> <img src="assets/img/ww/patty.jpg" class="img-responsive" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s" alt="Patty Jenkins"/></div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            
            <div class="point container-fluid" id="point4">
                <div class="overlay"></div>
                    <div class="text-center">
                        <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">Themes</h3>

                        <div class="wr-taglines">
                            
                            <h3 class="tagline" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">Wonder. Power. Courage.</h3>
                            <h3 class="tagline" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.3s">The future of justice begins with her</h3>
                            <h3 class="tagline" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s">Power. Grace. Wisdom. Wonder.</h3>
                        </div>
                        <div class="container">
                        <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.5s">
                            The movie's taglines reveal the over-arcing themes of this character; someone who is undeniably powerful, and  someone who cares deeply about making a difference that matters. Wonder Woman brings a unique perspective of Justice and Wisdom that juxtaposes mankind's incessant obsession with needless violence. She vows to fight for those who cannot fight for themselves. She may not be the hero we deserve, but she's the hero we need. </p>
                    </div>
                        </div>
            </div>
            
            
                    
                    <div class="point clearfix" id="point6">
                        <div class="container">
                            <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">Chris Pine and supporting cast</h3>
                            <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.3s">Chris Pine plays the role of Steve Trevor, Wonder Woman's love interest in the film. Just for starters, having him in the film at all is a big plus, since he's super talented and irresistibly likeable in all of his movies. Add on to that the chemistry between him and Gal, along with his witty quips, and Chris will no doubt be the comic highlight of the movie. Throw in names like Robin Wright, David Thewlis, Danny Huston, Lucy Davis and Connie Nielson, and it's plain to see that Wonder Woman has a cast that's oozing with talent.</p>
                           
                        </div>
                         <img src="assets/img/ww/chris-gal.jpg" class="img-responsive" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 0.3s" alt="Chris Pine Gal Gadot"/>
                           <img src="assets/img/ww/amazons.jpg" class="img-responsive" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.3s" alt="Wonder Woman Cast"/>
                    </div>
            
                <div class="point" id="point5">
                        <div class="container">
                            <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">Setting of the movie</h3>
                            <div class="row">
                                <div class="col-sm-6">
                                    <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                                        As promotional material has revealed thus far, the movie will visit various settings, from the breath-taking paradise isle of Thymescira, to the muddy trenches of World War 1. It introduces Diana to a world where women weren't particularly deemed on par with men in their society. Her unique worldview contrasting with the ideas of that era, will certainly prove to be comical as well as thought-provoking. And beyond that, this movie just looks amazing.
                                    </p>
                                   
                                </div>
                                <div class="col-sm-6">
                                     <img src="assets/img/ww/charge.gif" id="charge" class="img-responsive" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.3s" alt="Wonder Woman Amazons"/>
                                </div>
                            </div>                           
                        </div>
                        <div class="" id="shots">  
                            <img src="assets/img/ww/battle.jpg" class="" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s" alt="Wonder Woman World War 1"/>
                            <img src="assets/img/ww/thymescira.jpg" class="" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.5s" alt="Wonder Woman Thymescira"/>
                        </div>
                    </div>
            <img src="assets/img/ww/blue.jpg" id="blue" class="img-responsive"  alt="Wonder Woman Thymescira"/>
        </section>
            <section id="summary">
            <div class="container">
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-sm-12 text-center" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                        <p>
                            And if you're still not convinced why this movie will kick-ass, just watch all these amazing trailers:
                        </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                
            </div>
                <iframe width="33%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5lGoQhFb4NM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
                <iframe width="33%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1Q8fG0TtVAY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
                <iframe width="33%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/INLzqh7rZ-U" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
                <iframe width="33%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VSB4wGIdDwo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
                <iframe width="33%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HUCBxfHjayo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
                
                <iframe width="33%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e9waCtSVoZ0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </section>
        

  

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Here's What to Look Forward to in 2017</title>
	  <link>/thethingis//most-anticipated-movies-2017</link>
	  <author>Samanalie Dias Jayasinha</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-02-02T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/thethingis//most-anticipated-movies-2017</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <section class="header-sec1">
    <div class="overlay">
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row text-center">

                <div class="col-sm-12">
                    <div class="">
                        <h1>Most Anticipated Movies of 2017</h1>
                    </div>

                </div>

            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

</section>
<!--HEADER SECTION END-->


<section class="intro">
    <div class="container">
        <div class="row">
            <div class="col-sm-8 col-sm-offset-2">
                <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">2017 is shaping up to be an exciting year in Movies. There's sure to be at least a couple that are on everyone's radar, but with such a vast array of movies coming up, it's easy to miss out on a few. So for easy reference, here are some of the upcoming movie releases in 2017 that ooze potential, and have our curiosities piqued. <br/>(Note: This is not a comprehensive list, just some of the ones that I'm personally anticipating.)</p>
                <p class="instructions" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                    Hover over each movie, to see why you should be excited and to view the trailers (if you're on a mobile device, tap on a movie). You can also filter the movies by genre or popularity, and sort by release date or my level of anticipation.
                </p>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
</section>

<section class="sorters">
    <div class="container">
        <h2 class="subtitle">Filter</h2>
        <div id="filters" class="button-group">
            <button class="button is-checked" data-filter="*">show all</button>
            <button class="button" data-filter=".comic">Comic Book</button>
            <button class="button" data-filter=".action">Action</button>
            <button class="button" data-filter=".scifi">Science-Fiction</button>
            <button class="button" data-filter=".fantasy">Fantasy</button>
            <button class="button" data-filter=".drama">Drama</button>
            <button class="button" data-filter=".comedy">Comedy</button>
            <button class="button" data-filter=".thriller">Thriller</button>
            <button class="button" data-filter=".romance">Romance</button>
            <button class="button" data-filter=".known">Popular</button>
            <button class="button" data-filter=".unknown">Under the radar</button>
        </div>

       
        <h2 class="subtitle">Sort</h2>
        <div id="sorts" class="button-group">
            <!--<button class="button is-checked" data-sort-by="original-order">original order</button>-->
            <!--<button class="button" data-sort-by="name">Name</button>-->
            <button class="button is-checked" data-sort-by="level">Anticipation Level</button>
            <button class="button" data-sort-by="release">Release Date</button>
        </div>
    </div>
</section>

<section>



    <div class="grid">
        <div class="element-item comic action fantasy known" id="ww">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Wonder Woman</h3>
            <p class="release">2 June 2017</p>
            <p class="level">01</p>
            <span>My number 1 most anticipated movie of the year. Gal Gadot headlines the first standalone female superhero movie of the current era. The weight of the future of the DCEU rests on her shoulders, but I believe Wonder Woman will achieve the greatness she deserves. </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-ww">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item comic action fantasy known" id="jl">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Justice League</h3>
            <p class="release">17 November 2017</p>
            <p class="level">02</p>
            <span>Superman, Batman, Wonder Woman, The Flash, Aquaman, Green Lantern… the list goes on. Probably the greatest collection of superheroes to ever be assembled in one movie, Justice League would really have to work a miracle to not be entertaining.
            </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-jl">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item comic action drama known" id="logan">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Logan</h3>
            <p class="release">3 March 2017</p>
            <p class="level">03</p>
            <span>Supposedly Hugh Jackman's last outing as everyone's favourite mutant, Wolverine returns to the big-screen with a very different kind of superhero movie. The tone looks grim, and decidedly violent, but intermixed with drama and heavy emotional undertones. Also keep an eye out for the introduction of the next incarnation of Wolverine.
            </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-logan">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item action drama known" id="dunkirk">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Dunkirk</h3>
            <p class="release">21 July 2017</p>
            <p class="level">14</p>
            <span>A harrowing look at the horrors of war through the lense of Christopher Nolan, director of the Dark Knight trilogy and Inception. If you're a fan of Saving Private Ryan, something tells me, you're going to be a fan of Dunkirk as well.
            </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-dunkirk">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item scifi thriller known" id="alien">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Alien: Covenant</h3>
            <p class="release">19 May 2017</p>
            <p class="level">24</p>
            <span>The next chapter in the Alien saga, with director Ridley Scott returning to the helm, Alien Covenant looks to deliver a quality sci-fi horror movie, as it continuing the story introduced in Prometheus.
            </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-alien">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item comic action comedy scifi known" id="gog">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2</h3>
            <p class="release">5 May 2017</p>
            <p class="level">07</p>
            <span>Awesome 80s music, hilarious one-liners, kick-ass fight sequences, and baby groot! Need I say more?
            </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-gog">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item comic action fantasy known" id="thor">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Thor Ragnarok</h3>
            <p class="release">3 November 2017</p>
            <p class="level">08</p>
            <span>Thor vs The Hulk. We got a slight taste of it in The Avengers, but get ready to see it on a whole new level, when the two goliaths face-off gladiator style, in what's sure to be a crazy, action-packed movie. I don't know how they're gonna pull it off, but I'm definitely curious to see them try.</span>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item action scifi fantasy known" id="sw">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Star Wars Episode VIII: The Last Jedi</h3>
            <p class="release">15 December 2017</p>
            <p class="level">06</p>
            <span>The Skywalker Chronicles continue! It doesn't take a lot of convincing to get on board with the latest episode of Star Wars, especially coming on the heels of the triumphant Rogue One. More Luke Skywalker, can only mean good things. It will also likely be the last time we see Carrie Fischer as Princess Leia, so it will certainly be an emotional day at the theatre.
            </span>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item scifi action unknown" id="val">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Valerian and the city of a thousand planets</h3>
            <p class="release">21 July 2017</p>
            <p class="level">21</p>
            <span>A somewhat quirky-looking sci-fi adventure, with a ton of incredible visuals, I don't know much about Valerian, but I'm curious to learn more. Can Cara Delevingne finally prove once and for all that she's a legitimate actress, and help us all forget that awful dancey performance in Suicide Squad?</span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-val">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item drama romance unknown" id="space">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">The Space Between Us</h3>
            <p class="release">3 February 2017</p>
            <p class="level">26</p>
            <span>Imagine discovering the world for the very first time as a teenager. The Space Between Us has the interesting premise, of a boy, born on a space station on Mars, away from almost all human contact. As he journeys to Earth for the first time, the film explores new encounters, falling in love, and discovering your place in the world. </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-space">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item mystery drama unknown" id="before">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Before I Fall</h3>
            <p class="release">3 March 2017</p>
            <p class="level">12</p>
            <span>Repeating the same day over and over again is hardly a new premise for a movie. But Before I Fall isn't a flashy sci-fi action blockbuster. It's a quiet indie film, where one girl, while in the process of being doomed to repeat the same day again and again, must discover how even the smallest, most mundane moments can shape the course of the future, and to make every second count.</span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-before">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item action fantasy known" id="kong">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Kong Skull Island</h3>
            <p class="release">10 March 2017</p>
            <p class="level">15</p>
            <span>King Kong is back! And he's bigger than ever! Kong Skull Island will take us back to the 80s where we'll be introduced to the biggest incarnation of King Kong that we've seen yet. Why is he so big? Because, if all goes well, he'll be battling Godzilla on the big screen in the not too distant future. Also, the movie stars Tom Hiddleston, so that should be enough of a draw.
            </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-kong">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item comic action known" id="spider">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Spiderman Homecoming</h3>
            <p class="release">7 July 2017</p>
            <p class="level">05</p>
            <span>Yet another reboot of the Spiderman franchise, this time with Marvel onboard. While we should all be sorely tired of seeing yet another new iteration of the character, Spiderman Homecoming managed to do the impossible; it actually got me excited for it, with a charming and entertaining trailer, that somehow breathed new life into the character.
            </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-spider">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item fantasy romance known" id="beauty">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Beauty and the Beast</h3>
            <p class="release">17 March 2017</p>
            <p class="level">04</p>
            <span>Emma Watson and Dan Stevens bring the animated classic to life. Even if you've never seen the original animated Disney flick, the beautiful visuals, enchanting music, and a chance to see Hermione as Belle, is reason enough to look forward to Beauty and the Beast.
            </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-beauty">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item action comedy known" id="lego">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">The Lego Batman Movie</h3>
            <p class="release">10 February 2017</p>
            <p class="level">16</p>
            <span>Just when we'd all settled on Batman as the darkest, most serious superhero ever, here comes the Lego Batman Movie, to show us a completely different take on the Dark Knight. The trailers have been hilarious, poking fun at the stoic and dark nature of the character, with even a little jab at Batman v Superman. It looks to be a fun and entertaining movie going experience.
            </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-lego">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item action scifi known" id="power">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Power Rangers</h3>
            <p class="release">24 March 2017</p>
            <p class="level">10</p>
            <span>This brand new iteration of the Power Rangers seems to be oozing with cheese, but when you're talking about 5 teens who dress up in colourful super suits and fight monsters, it's pretty hard to avoid cheesiness. If you're willing to forgive the campiness, it just might be a fun call-back to your childhood. The special effects look cool enough.
            </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-power">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item action comedy known" id="kingsman">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Kingsman: The Golden Circle</h3>
            <p class="release">6 October 2017</p>
            <p class="level">09</p>
            <span>The first Kingsman movie was a wildly entertaining action film. With tons of fun parodies of typical spy genre tropes, along with some truly spectacular action scenes, it was a standout movie. If this sequel can be even half as entertaining as its predecessor, then count me in. Manners maketh a man!
            </span>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item action fantasy unknown" id="mummy">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">The Mummy</h3>
            <p class="release">9 June 2017</p>
            <p class="level">22</p>
            <span>Forget the goofy action comedy of the last decade. This is a reboot of the franchise, with Tom Cruise along for the ride. Will it be Mission Impossible with Mummies? Perhaps. But how could that possibly be a bad thing. Also, this time we'll be dealing with a female version of the monster.
            </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-mummy">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item action drama unknown" id="arthur">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">King Arthur Legend of the Sword</h3>
            <p class="release">12 May 2017</p>
            <p class="level">11</p>
            <span>Charlie Hunnam stars as the titular character in this origin-story of sorts. It doesn't look like any Arthurian tale we've ever seen before, and considering that this is from Guy Richie, the director of the Sherlock Holmes films and last year's criminally underrated Man from UNCLE, King Arthur Legend of the Sword looks to a movie worth seeing. 
            </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-arthur">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item drama sci-fi thriller unknown" id="circle">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">The Circle</h3>
            <p class="release">28 April 2017</p>
            <p class="level">20</p>
            <span>Any movie with Emma Watson has my attention. Throw in a plot of a nefarious Tech company that seems to be crossing the line of user privacy, the movie looks to be a timely exploration of some of the issues our society is facing today.</span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-circle">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item action scifi known" id="shell">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Ghost in the Shell</h3>
            <p class="release">31 March 2017</p>
            <p class="level">30</p>
            <span>Scarlette Johanson stars in Ghost in the Shell, a science-fiction movie adapted from a famous Japanese Manga of the same name. I'm not familiar with the original property, but the visuals look stunning, and the cinematic universe explored in the movie, seems intriguing enough to give it a watch.
            </span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-shell">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item comedy drama scifi unknown" id="col">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Colossal</h3>
            <p class="release">7 April 2017</p>
            <p class="level">17</p>
            <span>Anne Hathaway unwittingly remote controlling a gigantic monster in Japan. Yes it's as crazy as it sounds. It also sounds absolutely hilarious, and the trailer definitely sells the madness.</span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-col">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item action scifi unknown" id="belko">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">The Belko Experiment</h3>
            <p class="release">17 March 2017</p>
            <p class="level">28</p>
            <span>The Belko Experiment is one of those movies that makes you question, "what would you do if you were in that situation?" It's a horrifying premise, being trapped with your co-workers and being told to choose who lives and dies. It's sure to raise questions of morality vs survival, and it has Guardians of the Galaxy director James Gunn at the helm.</span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-belko">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item drama unknown" id="gifted">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Gifted</h3>
            <p class="release">7 April 2017</p>
            <p class="level">29</p>
            <span>Chris Evans takes a break from being everyone's favourite Captain, to play a young man raising his niece who is a child-prodigy. It's nice to see Chris Evans outside of an action role, and Gifted looks to be a touching and heart-warming tale of redemption, trust and family.</span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-gifted">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item action fantasy comedy known" id="pirates">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Men Tell No Tales</h3>
            <p class="release">26 May 2017</p>
            <p class="level">25</p>
            <span>The Pirates franchise doesn't quite excite us like it used to, but there's hope for Dead Men Tell No Tales, as it sees the return of Orlando Bloom, and hopefully a return to a tighter storyline focusing on characters we care about. And of course, Jack Sparrow is back, so at the very least, we'll see some hilarious antics.</span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-pirates">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item sci-fi thriller unknown" id="life">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Life</h3>
            <p class="release">24 March 2017</p>
            <p class="level">19</p>
            <span>Ryand Reynolds and Jake Gyllenhaal play astronauts on a space mission to Mars, where they discover evidence of extra-terrestrial life that isn't altogether friendly. Alien life threatening a space-crew isn't exactly a novel concept, but the trailer and the cast involved make this a movie worth getting excited about.</span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-life">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item drama comedy romance unknown" id="finest">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">Their Finest</h3>
            <p class="release">7 April 2017</p>
            <p class="level">14</p>
            <span>If Dunkirk is a little too intense for you, Their Finest examines World War 2 through a different perspective. A female screen-writer in a British film crew, must overcome stereotypes to do her part to help in the war. Though set in a difficult period, the film presents a heart-warming and comedic story, with charming performances by Gemma Arterton, Sam Claflin and Bill Nighy.</span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-finest">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item drama romance unknown" id="rachel">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">My Cousin Rachel</h3>
            <p class="release">14 July 2017</p>
            <p class="level">27</p>
            <span>If you like your period dramas with a darker flavour than typical Jane Austen-fare, then My Cousin Rachel looks to be right up your alley. Based on the popular Daphne Du Maurier novel, the film stars Sam Claflin and Rachel Weiz in a mysterious and twisted love affair. I haven't read the novel, but the trailer alone has me curious about this story.</span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-rachel">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item drama action thriller unknown" id="city">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">The Lost City of Z</h3>
            <p class="release">21 April 2017</p>
            <p class="level">23</p>
            <span>The Lost City of Z revolves around the real-life story of a British explorer on his search for a forgotten city in the depths of the amazon. The movie looks to blend adventure with the eeriness of the unknown, and stars Carlie Hunnam and Robert Pattinson, who just happens to be sporting a glorious beard. Uncharted territory indeed.</span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-city">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        <div class="element-item action known" id="wick">
            <div class="overlay"></div>
            <h3 class="name">John Wick: Chapter 2</h3>
            <p class="release">10 February 2017</p>
            <p class="level">18</p>
            <span>John Wick is back out of retirement, and kicking butt. Keanu Reeves, guns, action. Need I say more.</span>
            <a data-toggle="modal" data-target="#modal-wick">Trailer</a>
        </div>
        
    </div>

</section>






<div id="modal-ww" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1Q8fG0TtVAY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-jl" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fIHH5-HVS9o" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-logan" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DekuSxJgpbY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-dunkirk" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/F-eMt3SrfFU" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-alien" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H0VW6sg50Pk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-gog" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dW1BIid8Osg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-val" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DX6LPS_PcCw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-space" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x73-573aWfs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-before" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q3Zyy4ZXegE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-kong" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YAbI4w95cTE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-spider" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xrzXIaTt99U" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-beauty" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e3Nl_TCQXuw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>

<div id="modal-lego" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rGQUKzSDhrg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-power" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5kIe6UZHSXw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-mummy" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IjHgzkQM2Sg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-arthur" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6rbPTQIdjmY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-circle" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lm9sshQhAZw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-shell" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6s9JEcRb5I4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-col" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RT2khohvjLE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-belko" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jP2Ow2CX6OQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-gifted" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tI01wBXGHUs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-pirates" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1xo3af_6_Jk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-life" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LeLsJfGmY_Y" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-finest" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nEvATtGnm5k" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-rachel" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Gp_8OYkGds0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-city" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hjqtP459uo8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
<div id="modal-wick" class="modal fade" role="dialog">
  <div class="modal-dialog">
    <div class="modal-content">
        <button type="button" class="close" data-dismiss="modal">&times;</button>
        <div class="modal-body">
            <iframe width="100%" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ChpLV9AMqm4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The thing is... Rogue One is Star Wars at its Best</title>
	  <link>/thethingis//rogue-one-movie-review</link>
	  <author>Samanalie Dias Jayasinha</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-01-08T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/thethingis//rogue-one-movie-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <section id="intro">
    <img src="assets/img/starwars/banner.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Rogue One banner" />
    <h1 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
        <span>Rogue One is Star Wars at its Best</span>
                    </h1>
</section>
        <section id="sec1">
            <div class="container" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                <p>
                    Rogue One is exactly what its subtitle suggests; a story based in the Star Wars universe. It sits between Episode III (Revenge of the Sith) and Episode IV (A New Hope). In fact, it literally tells the story of the first couple of lines in the Opening Crawl of Episode IV.</p>
            </div>
                
        </section>
<img src="assets/img/starwars/crawl.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Episode IV Opening Crawl" />
        <section id="sec11">
                <div class="container" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                <p>In summary, Rogue One is the tale of rag-tag members of a fledgling Rebel Alliance coming together to steal the plans to the Galactic Empire's superweapon, The Deathstar. It acts as the launching pad for the events that lead to the final take-down of Empire, and fleshes out the entire Star Wars universe in a very satisfying way. Indeed it's a brilliant achievement on the part of this film, that it takes one line of exposition, and turns it into a well-rounded and entertaining story.</p>
            </div>
        </section>


        <section id="sec2">
            <h2 class="subheading text-center">The Cast</h2>
            <div class="container-fluid">
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-sm-4" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                        <img src="assets/img/starwars/cast-bad.jpg" class="one img-responsive" alt="Rogue One Cast" />
                    </div>
                    <div class="col-sm-4 text-center" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                        
                        <p>
                            While the movie centers on the rebels, the primary focus rests on Jyn Erso, played by a quietly strong Felicity Jones, a young woman who is haunted by her family's connection to the Empire. She is supported by strong performances from Diego Luna as Captain Cassian Andor, Mads Mikkelsen as Galen Erso, Donnie Yen as Chirrut Imwe and Ben Mendelsohn as the deliciously villainous Orson Krennic. There are many other famous faces and engaging performances scattered throughout the film, and as a whole the cast gels well together to bring us, what is easily, the most diverse Star Wars movie we have ever seen. 
</p>
                        
                    </div>
                    <div class="col-sm-4" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                        <img src="assets/img/starwars/cast-good.jpg" class="two img-responsive" alt="Rogue One Cast" />
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </section>


 <section id="sec3">
     <div class="container">
         <div class="row">
             <div class="col-sm-9" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                 <p>There are electric moments of chemistry between the cast members, be it a deep rooted friendship between Chirrut and Baze, or the palpable sexual tension between Jyn and Cassian. It's been awhile since I saw a movie where the male and female lead don’t share a single on-screen kiss, and yet have as much chemistry as Felicity Jones and Diego Luna.</p>
             </div>
             <div class="col-sm-3" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                 <img src="assets/img/starwars/jyn-cassian.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Rogue One Cast" />
             </div>
         </div>
         <div class="row">
             <div class="col-sm-6" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                 <img src="assets/img/starwars/k2so.png" class="img-responsive" alt="Rogue One Cast" />
             </div>
             <div class="col-sm-6" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                 <p>A special mention of the droid K-2SO, voiced and performed by Alan Tudyk. He easily became an instant stand-out in the movie, stealing the scene whenever he was on screen. His witty and sarcastic remarks, delivered in Tudyk's dead-pan matter-of-fact tone of voice, had the theatre audience laughing out loud.
</p>
             </div>
         </div>
     </div>
</section>

        <section id="sec4">
            <h2 class="subheading text-center">The Action</h2>
<img src="assets/img/starwars/fight.gif" class="fullsize img-responsive" alt="Rogue One Cast" />
            <div class="container">
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-sm-12">                    


                        <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                            The action is well choreographed, and feels dangerous. In an age where nearly every action movie borrows from the school of Jason Bourne's quick-cut mayhem, it's wonderful to see the action through steady, long-held camera shots. It allows us to truly appreciate each moment of choreography. Donnie Yen especially lends a sense of believability to his action scenes, as he obviously knows what he's doing. The movie as a whole divides its action into two halves, where the first hour of the film has more close-quartered action, while the final hour moves to a grander scale with epic space battles. Both are handled exceptionally well.</p>
                        <p class="note" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                           One issue I had: The notion of debilitating a Storm Trooper using hand to hand combat seemed a little too convenient. <em>I mean, that is armour that they're wearing, right?</em></p>
                    </div>

                </div>


            </div>
        </section>



        <section id="sec5" class="text-center">
            <div class="container">
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-sm-12" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                        <h2 class="subheading">The Nostalgia</h2>
                        <p>
                            The great thing about Rogue One is that you can go in as a complete Star Wars noob, and still have a fairly enjoyable movie-going experience, because it stands on its own as a well-constructed story. But if you're familiar with Star Wars lore, and if you've watched the previous movies, you're going to be positively gleeful. It has numerous appearances by familiar faces throughout the Star Wars anthology, and it perfectly bridges together the Prequels with the Original Trilogy. While Hollywood has been overrun with sequels/prequels/reboots that all try their best to play on our nostalgia, Rogue One has done it the best so far. Beyond merely referencing an existing franchise, it actually builds on it and improves it.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div class="col-sm-12" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s">
                      <img src="assets/img/starwars/atat.jpg" class="fullsize img-responsive" alt="Rogue One ATAT" />
                    </div>
                </div>

            </div>
        </section>


        <section class="text-center" id="sec6">
            <h2 class="subheading">That Scene</h2>
            <img src="assets/img/starwars/vader.jpg" class="fullsize img-responsive" alt="Darth Vader" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s"/>
            <div class="container">
                <div class="row">
                    
                    <div class="col-sm-12">
                        <p  data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">If you've seen the movie, then you know what I'm talking about. </p>
                        <p  data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s">
                           If you've seen the trailer, then it should come as no surprise to you that Darth Vader makes an appearance in this movie. He's not in it extensively, but his presence is definitely felt in a powerful way. No spoilers, but there's a scene towards the end of the movie involving Lord Vader that was simply breath-taking. I've been a casual Star Wars fan for a long time, and I've watched every movie in the series, but I never really understood why Darth Vader was often considered the number 1 villain in movie history. I never really understood the menace or fear that the characters in the movies seemed to feel in his presence. That was until I saw Rogue One. Once you see the movie, you'll understand.

                        </p>
                        
                    </div>
                </div>

            </div>
        </section>
       
    <section id="summary">
            <div class="container">
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-sm-12 text-center" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                        <p>
                            Rogue One is action-packed, engaging and thoroughly entertaining. Some viewers might find the first half of the movie a little slow-moving, but the pay-off at the end is well-worth it.  I'm going to say something a little controversial here; but understand that I didn't grow up with the original trilogy and I found the prequels somewhat lacking. Episode VII: The Force Awakens was a fun ride and I definitely enjoyed it. But the thing is Rogue One just might be my favourite Star Wars movie.

</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </section>
        

  

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The thing is... Warcraft is the Best Video Game Movie Thus Far</title>
	  <link>/thethingis//warcraft-movie-review</link>
	  <author>Samanalie Dias Jayasinha</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-12T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/thethingis//warcraft-movie-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	             <button id="switch">Switch Theme</button>

    <section id="splash">
        <a class="splash-half orc" id="orc">
            <img src="assets/img/warcraft/splash-orc.jpg" alt="Orcs" />
        </a>
        <a class="splash-half human" id="human">
            <img src="assets/img/warcraft/splash-human.jpg" alt="Humans"/>
        </a>
        <span>Choose Your Side</span>
    </section>
    <div id="page-content">
        <section class="" id="intro">
            <div class="container">
                <div class="row text-center">
                    <div class="col-sm-12">
                        <h1 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                        <span><img src="assets/img/warcraft/title.png" class="img-responsive" alt="Warcraft"/></span> is the Best Video Game Movie Thus Far
                    </h1>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </section>

        <img src="assets/img/warcraft/warcraft2.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Hypogriff in Flight" />

        <section id="sec1">
            <div class="container" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                <p>
                    Movies based on Video Games have established a well-proven stereotype; shallow, campy, over-the-top and almost always, disappointing. They've ranged from low-budget cheesiness like Mortal Kombat, to big-budget star-driven wanna-be epics like Prince of Persia. </p>
                <p>
                    Warcraft had every chance to follow in those exact same footsteps, and when initially presented with its world, it may seem like more of the same shallow, effects-driven fan-service that we've seen before. But after seeing the movie, I'm extremely happy to conclude that this was without a doubt, the best Video Game Movie that I have seen thus far. </p>
            </div>
        </section>


        <section id="sec2">
            <div class="container">
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-sm-12 text-center" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                        <p>
                            As a precursor, I admit that I haven't played the World of Warcraft game, that the movie is based off of. I have however played Warcraft 3, the real-time strategy incarnation of the game. The characters in this movie were all new to me, so I didn't have much fore-knowledge going into the movie.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </section>

        <section id="sec3">
            <div class="container">
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-sm-12">
                        <h2 class="subheading text-center">A different perspective</h2>

                        <img src="assets/img/warcraft/warcraft1.jpg" class="img-responsive pull-left" alt="Orcs and Humans meet" />


                        <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                            Warcraft tells the story of a first encounter between two very different civilizations; the Orcs and Humans. Each race has its own dynamics and culture, which are very much at odds with each other, which in turn sparks a war. The Orcs are the instigators, while the Humans are merely reactionary.</p>
                        <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                            In these instances, we're mostly used to seeing stories told from the Human perspective. If there's an Alien Invasion, it's from the Human perspective. If there's a battle against some supernatural force, it's from the Human perspective. Even prior fantasy stories, such as Lord of the Rings are mostly based around the perspective of human or human-like races. In fact, we've gotten pretty used to seeing Orcs as mindless beasts who are only interested in death and destruction. </p>
                    </div>

                </div>


            </div>
        </section>



        <section id="sec4">
            <div class="container">
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-sm-6" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                        <p>
                            Warcraft breaks this trend, by making the Orcs the most compelling characters onscreen. They have internal conflicts, wavering loyalties, intricate tribal traditions and hierarchies, and a deep sense of honour. They do reign a fair amount of chaos on the Human world, leaving destruction in their wake, but no one could accuse these creatures of being unthinking beasts. Even the introduction to our primary Orc protagonist, war-chieftain Durotan, is by his pregnant wife's side, as they playfully discuss their future child. This paints a very different picture from the Orcs that we've grown accustomed to seeing, and it is truly refreshing.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div class="col-sm-6" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s">
                        <img src="assets/img/warcraft/orc2.png" class="img-responsive" alt="Durotan"/>
                    </div>
                </div>

            </div>
        </section>


        <section id="sec5">
            <div class="container">
                <div class="row">

                    <div class="col-sm-4" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                        <img src="assets/img/warcraft/human1.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Lothar"/>
                    </div>
                    <div class="col-sm-4" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s">
                        <p>
                            The majority of the character development throughout the movie remains with the Orcs. There are moments where we delve into the human characters and get a glimpse of their own histories and motivations, but this is minimal and can sometimes even seem a little flat in comparison.</p>
                        <p>This movie is really about the story of Durotan and his people's journey to find a home. I wonder if the majority of the criticism that has been levelled at this movie is due to the fact that the usual "heroes" are less compelling than the brutish creatures. This is a fresh take on Fantasy, and the Video Game movie genre as a whole, so I found myself pleasantly surprised.</p>

                    </div>
                    <div class="col-sm-4" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.3s">
                        <img src="assets/img/warcraft/durotan.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Durotan"/>
                    </div>
                </div>

            </div>
        </section>
        <div class="battle text-center">
            <img src="assets/img/warcraft/battle.gif" alt="Warcraft Battle Scene"/>
        </div>
        <section id="sec6" class="text-center">
            <div class="container">
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-sm-12" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                        <h2 class="subheading">Action, Character &amp; Effects</h2>
                        <p>
                            It would do this film a great disservice if I didn't mention the epic, yes absolutely EPIC battle sequences it depicts. Director Duncan Jones expertly captures the action up-close without it ever feeling muddled or confusing. You feel the weight of every hammer's fall, and the sharpness of each sword. The action scenes were exceedingly entertaining, and sometimes I found myself even cringing whenever a particularly heavy blow would fall. It felt like being in the middle of the fight, and even if you see this movie just for the action, I believe it would be time well-spent.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </section>
        
        <section id="note">
            <div class="container">
            <div class="row">
                <div class="col-sm-12">
                    <img src="assets/img/warcraft/mix2.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Garona" />
                
                    <p>A note on Paula Patton's character, Garona, a half-breed Orc character; throughout the marketing campaign for the movie, she was shown in Orc garb, which was quite revealing, while she struck a provocative pose. Now I understand that the target audience of this movie is primarily made up of the younger male demographic, so Hollywood was just being Hollywood by marketing her character that way. It's an annoying aspect of the entertainment industry in general, but it is what it is.  As I watched the movie however, I was pleasantly surprised to see that as the story progressed, Garona became more "clothed" if I could use that term. Her character wasn't just eye-candy. She got full-bodied armour, she fought viciously in battle, she integrated into a new society, and she dealt with several emotional storylines. The final act of the movie even hinted that she may have an even more important role to play should the series continue in the future. All in all, it was exceedingly refreshing to see an intelligent portrayal of a female character in a video game movie.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                </div>
        </section>

        <section id="sec7">
            <div data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 0.2s">
                <img src="assets/img/warcraft/scenery1.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Scenery"/>
            </div>
            <div data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.2s">
                <img src="assets/img/warcraft/scenery2.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Scenery" />
            </div>
        </section>
        <section id="sec8">
            <div class="container text-center" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-sm-12">
                        <p>
                            The sceneries and environment are expansive and breath-taking. It often feels surreal; like a painting brought to life. This feeling invades the whole look of the movie, where it may feel like you are in the middle of a Video Game rather than a traditional movie environment. Movies tend to always lean towards some sense realism, even when depicting Fantasy worlds. But Warcraft lets go of realism, and fully embraces the largeness of its universe. It could have easily been quite cheesy, but Duncan Jones handles it with such finesse that keeps it within a sense of wonderment, rather than incredulity.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </section>

        <section id="sec9">
            <img src="assets/img/warcraft/mix.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Warcraft Poster" />
            <div class="container">

                <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                    All in all, Warcraft deals with the traditional notions of Light vs Darkness, Good vs Evil, Tradition vs New-Thinking. It also explores deeper themes of loyalty, friendship, bravery and finding one's place in the world. The film boasts fantastic special effects, and the motion capture work on the Orcs is remarkable. It breaks norms, in making the "ugly beasts" the main focus of the film, and gives its characters intelligent and compelling story arcs. So despite what the majority of film critics seem to think, the thing is, Warcraft is the best Video Game Movie thus far, at least in my opinion.</p>
            </div>

        </section>

    </div>



	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The thing is... The Lord of the Rings is a story of The Unexpected Hero</title>
	  <link>/thethingis//the-lord-of-the-rings-unexpected-hero</link>
	  <author>Samanalie Dias Jayasinha</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-07-12T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/thethingis//the-lord-of-the-rings-unexpected-hero</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <body>

    <section class="" id="intro">
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row text-center">
                <div class="col-lg-8 col-lg-offset-2 col-md-12 col-md-offset-0 col-sm-11 col-sm-offset-0">
                    <h1 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                        <span>The Lord of the Rings is a story of </span><br/>The Unexpected Hero
                    </h1>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>

    <section class="" id="sec1">
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row text-center">
                <div class="col-sm-12">
                    <p class="emph bold">Every great story needs a Hero.</p>

<p><span class="emph">The Lord of The Rings</span> by J R R Tolkein, is widely considered to be one of the greatest works of Fantasy Literature ever written; and for good reason. It spans a rich and expansive world, and offers a story that is altogether epic in scope but deeply personal in its telling. Within this world, there are many characters explored, each championing the cause of their side; and as with all great stories, there is a hero to be found.</p>
                    <p>Who is the Hero in <span class="emph">The Lord of the Rings?</span></p> <p>A traditional hero in our mind is the one who fights grand battles and achieves great glory. But J R R Tolkien chooses to present us with a different idea for a hero. </p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>

    <section class="quote" id="quote1">
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row text-center">
                <div class="col-sm-12">
                    <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s"><span>&ldquo;</span>All that is gold does not glitter<span>&rdquo;</span></h3>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>

    <section class="" id="sec2">
        <div class="overlay"></div>
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row text-center">
                <div class="col-sm-9" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.3s">
                    <p>A character like Aragorn certainly seems primed to be the ultimate vehicle of heroism. But even he is not introduced as a confident and established hero, but as a grimy and weatherworn Ranger. Beneath the mud and grime however, is a leader of men and the heir to the throne of Gondor. Aragorn struggles with self-doubt, but eventually overcomes his insecurities to claim his destiny as a great warrior, leading a great host against the enemy, and finally being crowned as king. By all means, this is the Hero's journey that we have come to expect.</p>
                    <p>
                        But anyone who has delved into the Lord of the Rings, would probably not point to Aragorn as the primary Hero of the tale. He certainly is one of the many heroes in the series, yet somehow, despite being the quintessential personification of heroism, it is the characters that surprise us that seem to have the greater impact in the course of the story.
                    </p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
            
    </section>
    
    

    <section class="" id="sec3">
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row text-center">
                <div class="col-sm-12">
                    <p>
                        The Unexpected Hero is a recurring theme in The Lord of the Rings, and Tolkien begins this with Frodo Baggins. Much is made of a simple hobbit being chosen as the Ring Bearer, amidst the presence of warriors, wizards and wise men. Frodo never sees himself playing a large or even significant role, merely a temporary steward of the Ring until stronger and wiser folk can take over. And yet it is he that becomes the bearer of the greatest burden, precisely because of his humility and unassuming nature. It harkens to the famous adage that perhaps the greatest Heroes are the ones that do not pursue its glories.
                    </p>

                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>

    
    <div class="spacer" id="spacer1">
        <img src="assets/img/lotr/rivendell.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Frodo in Rivendell"/>
    </div>
    
    <section class="quote" id="quote2">
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row text-center">
                <div class="col-sm-12">
                    
                        <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s"><span>&ldquo;</span>Even the smallest person can change the course of the future<span>&rdquo;</span></h3>
                    
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>

    <section class="" id="sec4">
        <div class="overlay"></div>
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row">
                <div class="col-sm-7 col-sm-offset-5 text-left">
                    <p>
                        Once Frodo becomes the Ring Bearer, we settle in for a charming story of how our brave little Hobbit will overcome his trials to defeat the evil forces that surround him and triumph as the ultimate Hero. We are now one step into the Unexpected Hero theme. But as the plot progresses, events do not unfold the way we expect. Despite being pure-hearted and good-intentioned, Frodo progressively crumbles under the burden of being the Ring Bearer. Despite being essentially our main protagonist, by the latter-end of the tale, he makes unwise decisions, treats Sam unfairly, is undiscerning of Gollum's treachery, and finally is unable to resist the temptation of the One Ring, succumbing to his desire and deciding to hold on to it instead of destroying it. That, is certainly not heroic. Now we are pulled in one step deeper into the twist of the Unexpected Hero. As Frodo steadily shrinks in heroism, Tolkien introduces to us another.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Another, who begins his journey as an insignificant gardener, and is pulled into the story by mere happen-chance and dropping of eaves, if you will. </p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>

    <section class="quote" id="quote3">
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row text-center">
                <div class="col-sm-12">
                    
                    <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s"><span>&ldquo;</span>
                        
                        <p><i>Gandalf:</i> Confound it all, Samwise Gamgee. Have you been eavesdropping?  </p>
                        
                        <p><i>Sam:</i> I ain't been droppin' no eaves sir, honest.</p>
                        <span>&rdquo;</span></h3>
                    
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>
    <section class="" id="sec5">
        <div class="overlay"></div>
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row text-center">
                <div class="col-sm-12">
                    <p>
                        Samwise Gamgee is presented to us as the "stupid, fat hobbit". The sidekick to the story. At least, an insignificant companion to the Fellowship, and at best, a support system for our main protagonist. He certainly doesn't fit the bill of a Hero, and we never expect him to be one. But by the end of the story, it is indeed Sam who emerges as the Hero. It is Sam who wades into the river to follow his master into Mordor, refusing to let him go alone. Sam, who sacrifices his rations for Frodo's sake, going hungry at times during their difficult journey. Sam, who remains loyal to their friendship despite the seeds of discord sown by Gollum. Sam, who faces his fears and risks everything to fight the monstrous spider, Shelob, and confronts a band of Orcs to rescue Frodo. And in perhaps one of the most powerful scenes of the tale, it is Sam who carries his friend up the side of Mount Doom, when Frodo has lost all will.
                    </p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>
    <section class="quote" id="quote4">
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row text-center">
                <div class="col-sm-7">
                    <h3 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s"><span>&ldquo;</span>
                        I can't carry it for you, <br/>but I can carry you.
                        <span>&rdquo;</span></h3>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>
    <section class="" id="sec6">
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row text-center">
                <div class="col-sm-12">
                    <p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.3s">
                        Other characters hold true to this theme as well. Merry and Pippin are introduced as mischief-makers, and the comic relief of the series. However, by the end, Merry has ridden into battle with the army of Rohan, and bravely stabs the Lord of the Nazgûl, thus enabling Eowyn to vanquish him. And Pippin has gone from being an incessant annoyance, and the thorn in Gandalf's side, to being a Guard of the Citadel of Gondor, helping Gandalf to save Faramir's life from the insanity of his father and even fighting in the army during the final assault on the Gates of Mordor. Eowyn is presented as a shieldmaiden of Rohan, constantly left behind as the men of her kingdom ride to battle, and seemingly relegated to being an unfortunate and rejected love-interest for Aragorn. But she rises above these circumstances to fight in the battle of the Pelennor Fields, and finally defeat the Witch King of Angmar, doing what even Aragorn and Gandalf could not do.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>
    <section class="" id="sec7">
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row text-center">
                <div class="col-sm-8 col-sm-offset-2" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.3s">
                    <p>Tolkien births an important idea in our minds; that a Hero does not always begin his journey as one. It teaches us to remember that even if our own story thus far has seemed insignificant and disappointing, there is coming a time when we may rise above it. Some may walk the path of heroism their whole life, and be exactly what we expect. </p>
                    <p>But the thing is, Heroes can also be unexpected, both to those around them, <br>as well as to themselves.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>
    <section class="quote" id="quote5">
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row text-center">
                <div class="col-sm-12">
                   <h3>
                        <span>&ldquo;</span>
                       <p><i>Frodo:</i> I wish it need not have happened in my time</p>
                        <br/>
                       <p><i>Gandalf:</i> So do I, and so do all who live to see such times. <br>But that is not for them to decide. All we have to decide is what to do with the time that is given us.</p>
                        <span>&rdquo;</span>
                    </h3>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Jungle Book is an Adventure for the Eyes</title>
	  <link>/thethingis//the-jungle-book-review</link>
	  <author>Samanalie Dias Jayasinha</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-06-12T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/thethingis//the-jungle-book-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	         <div class="portion">
        <div class="inner">
            <section class="" id="intro">
                <div class="container">
                    <div class="row text-center">
                        <div class="col-lg-8 col-lg-offset-2 col-md-8 col-md-offset-2 col-sm-10 col-sm-offset-1">
                            <h1 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the top after 0.2s">
                   The Jungle Book is an Adventure for the Eyes
                        </h1>
                        </div>
                    </div>



                    <div data-scroll-reveal="enter from the top after 0.2s" class="col-sm-offset-2 col-sm-8">
                        <p>The one thing that you must know, when going in to see Disney's latest movie, The Jungle Book, is that 95% of what you see is entirely computer generated. The reason you should know this going in, is because 5 minutes into the film, you're going to completely forget that fact. And that is precisely what makes this a movie worth watching.</p>
                    </div>

                </div>
            </section>
        </div>
    </div>


    <section id="story">
        <div class="overlay">
            <div class="container">
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-sm-offset-1 col-sm-10">

                        <h2>Story</h2>
                        <p>As far as story goes, there isn't a lot that's going on. The plot follows Mowgli as he makes the journey across the jungle on his quest to reach the "man village." Along the way he crosses a myriad of environments and encounters various wildlife, some friendly, and some not so much. The overall story arc is quite predictable, and delivers pretty much the plot you would expect. Good triumphs over evil of course, our main protagonist being the beacon of hope and the voice that rallies everyone together. </p>

                        <p>Despite this however, the movie manages to keep its viewer engaged, not so much because we are ever in suspense as to whether Mowgli will eventually triumph, but because we are so invested in the environment and the captivating world that we see. We care about Mowgli, and more impressively, the movie makes us care about the CGI animals as well.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>



    <section id="effects" class="text-center">

        <img src="assets/img/jb/effects.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="effects"/>
        <h2>Effects</h2>
        <div class="inner" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the top after 0.2s">
            <div class="overlay">
                <div class="container">
                    <div class="row">
                        <div class="col-sm-8 col-sm-offset-2">
                            <p>CGI Technology continues to make impressive leaps and bounds in creating worlds that do not exist and making them wholly believable to viewers. This is often easier when the world being created is something of fantasy and science-fiction, an alien world or a mythical creature. But when CGI can authentically mimic things that we are essentially familiar with, then it deserves special praise. This is the case in The Jungle Book. Although the idea of talking animals and a human child living alongside them and communicating with them is a branch of fantasy, the appearance, movements and behaviour of the animals are all based upon reality.
                            </p>
                        </div>
                        <div class="col-sm-6">
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div id="animals">
            <div class="overlay">
            <div class="container">
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-sm-6">
                        <p>As I said at the beginning of this review, quite early on in the movie viewing process, it becomes easy to forget that we aren't watching real living, breathing wildlife. It becomes easy to imagine that the child actor is really caressing the course fur of a real trained Wolf or Jaguar, or is riding on the belly of a real trained Bear. But he isn't. In reality, he's interacting with a static figure covered in blue felt on the end of a stick. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div class="col-sm-6" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                        <img src="assets/img/jb/bear.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="baloo"/>
                    </div>

                </div>
                <div class="row animalrow">
                    <div class="col-sm-4" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.3s">
                        <img src="assets/img/jb/raksha.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="raksha"/>
                    </div>
                    <div class="col-sm-4" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s">
                        <img src="assets/img/jb/bageera.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="bageera"/>
                    </div>
                    <div class="col-sm-4" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.5s">
                        <img src="assets/img/jb/loui.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="louie"/>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-sm-12">
                        <p class="text-center">It goes beyond just the mere look of the animals; it's right down to the way each animal behaves and every minute movement that really sells the effect. The fact that the movie makes the wildlife and interactions so believable is truly a credit to the Special Effects department at Disney.
                        </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
                </div>
        </div>
    </section>


    <section id="acting" class="text-center">
        <div class="container-fluid">
            <div class="row">

                <div class="mowgli">
                    <img src="assets/img/jb/mowgli.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="mowgli"/>


                    <h2>Acting</h2>
                    <p  data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.2s">While the CGI Animators deserve high praise for the authenticity of the world that is presented in the movie, the burden of driving the emotional connection we feel to it, is borne almost entirely by the young star of the movie, Neel Sethi. He makes the difference of it not being merely a visually stunning and believable environment, but one that we get emotionally invested in, with characters that we care about. It certainly is an impressive feat when you consider that this is his first feature film and he was a mere 10 years old during filming. His acting is mostly convincing, and never exaggerated, and any moments where it is evident that he is acting are easily forgiven when the camera catches his deep engaging gaze. Also, it doesn't hurt that he is incredibly adorable and feels like the mischievous little brother we all wish we had.</p>
                </div>

            </div>

            <div class="row">
                <div class="cast" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
                    <p>
                        The movie also boasts a powerhouse voice-acting cast; of these the most recognizable voices provided by Ben Kingsley, Bill Murray, Lupita Nyong'o, Idris Elba, Scarlett Johansson and Christopher Walken. Bill Murray especially shines as the lovable Baloo and steals the show whenever he's on screen (or should I say, whenever his voice is heard). The comedy is ever present, while being grounded somewhat to make it more believable, but anyone would be hard-pressed to not immediately fall in love with that silly bear. Scarlet Johansson is also quite notable, and despite having a smaller role, completely consumes the screen time as the sinister snake Kaa. Idris Elba also delivers a commanding performance as the fearsome tiger Shere Khan.
                    </p>
                    <img src="assets/img/jb/voice-cast.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="cast"/>
                    
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>

    <section id="tension">
        <div class="overlay">
        <div class="container">
        <h2>Tension</h2>
            <div class="row">
                <div class="col-sm-7">
                    <p  data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.2s">
            There's a great tension in the deeper story of The Jungle Book, especially in terms of the character motivations. There are compelling themes of family and friendship, but I found a more complex theme behind Shere Khan's motivations. There is no doubt that he is the essential antagonist of the story, and painted on the surface as the typical villain. But upon reflection, one has to wonder whether his qualms about Mowgli were not unfounded. His prior experience with man has been as that of an invader and a disruptor of the natural way of the jungle. Man brings with him the "red flower", fire that destroys everything it touches. In fact, all the animals of the jungle fear it for this very reason, and so rightly they should. </p>
                </div>
                <div class="col-sm-5">
                    <img  data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 0.3s" src="assets/img/jb/fire.gif" class="img-responsive" alt="fire" />
                </div>
            </div>
        
            <div class="row">
                <div class="col-sm-7">
                    <img  data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 0.3s" src="assets/img/jb/snake.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="kaa" />
                </div>
                <div class="col-sm-5">
            <p  data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.2s">This is a tension we see in our own world, where nature has suffered much at the hands of human-beings. So Shere Khan is almost justified in his motivations, if not his actions. In the end, even while Mowgli tries to stand up to the tiger's tyranny using fire, he ends up causing destruction despite his best efforts. It raises an interesting question as to whether man can ever truly co-exist peacefully with Nature, without inadvertently causing its ruin.
        </p>
                </div>
            </div>
            </div>
    </section>


    <section id="final">
        <div class="overlay">
        <div class="container">
            <div class="row">
                <div class="col-sm-8 col-sm-offset-2">
                    <h2>Conclusion</h2>
        <p>
            The Jungle Book is a thrilling adventure film, which captivates its audience with stunning environments, amazing renderings of nature and compelling characters. The story is nothing new and won't deliver much in terms of surprises and plot twists, but The Thing is, the movie still manages to engage its viewers right to the end based on the strength of its incredible visual effects and effective performances.

        </p>
                </div>
            </div>
        
            </div>
        </div>
    </section>


    <section id="comments" class="container">
        <div id="disqus_thread"></div>

        <script>
            /**
             * RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
             * LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables
             */
            /*
            var disqus_config = function () {
            this.page.url = PAGE_URL; // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
            this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
            };
            */
            (function () { // DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE
                var d = document,
                    s = d.createElement('script');

                s.src = '//samanaliethethingis.disqus.com/embed.js';

                s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
                (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
            })();
        </script>
        <noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript" rel="nofollow">comments powered by Disqus.</a>
        </noscript>


    </section>

    
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>BvS is Different</title>
	  <link>/thethingis//bvs-is-different</link>
	  <author>Samanalie Dias Jayasinha</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-03-12T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/thethingis//bvs-is-different</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <section class="container-fluid intro">
<div class="row">

<div class="col-lg-4 col-lg-offset-4 col-md-8 col-md-offset-2 col-sm-10 col-sm-offset-1">

<h3 class="warning">*Warning* Spoilers ahead. If you haven't seen the movie yet, I would encourage you to watch it before you read this.</h3>

</div>
</div>

</section>

<section class="container-fluid aside">
<div class="overlay"> </div>
<div class="row">

<div class="col-sm-10 col-sm-offset-1">

<p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the top after 0.2s"><span class="italic">Just on a side note;</span> several months ago, during the height of my anticipation for the then upcoming Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice movie, a funny realization struck me. Clark Kent's mother is named Martha Kent. And Bruce Wayne's mother is named Martha Wayne. I was marveling (no pun intended), that two of DC Comics' greatest heroes have mothers with the exact same first name. I even joked about it with friends, saying 'you would think that they would have at least tried to find different names for such prominent characters in the story.' I mildly wondered to myself if they would have to awkwardly shrug that off in the film and make it not seem like such a blaring coincidence. Never in a million years did I think that that one idea would end up being the lynch pin for the events in BvS. </p>
</div>
</div>

</section>


<section class="container-fluid review-sec1">
<div class="overlay"> </div>
<div class="row">

<div class="col-sm-8 col-sm-offset-2">

<p>Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice was probably the most unique movie I have ever seen in the superhero genre. I cannot with a clear conscience say that it was the best superhero movie I have ever seen. But without a doubt, it was the superhero movie that made me think the most. Walking out of the theatre, my mind was reeling with a plethora of mysteries, plot points, character arcs and questions. Sitting in the theatre, I hardly had time to process one scene of intense character drama, before I was whisked away to another scene of epic special effects, before cutting into yet another scene of dense philosophical discussion. I couldn’t switch my brain off for even a second, because even a spectacular fight sequence was crafted with such care and detail, that there were dozens of appreciable elements floating in the nooks and crannies of the scene. Sometimes the editing even felt jarring and erratic. </p>
<p>There was just too much to be seen, there was just so much of this world to be explored, and if I blinked I would miss it. So I soaked it all in. BvS kept me on my toes the entire time… <span class="italic">and this was a good thing.</span>
</p>
</div>
</div>

</section>


<section class=" review-sec2">
<div class="container">
<div class="row">

<div class="col-sm-12">


</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<div class="container-fluid">
<div class="row">
<div id="levity">
<div class="overlay"></div>
<div class="container">
<p>As a general rule I have appreciated almost all comic book movie adaptations (I could even appreciate the bold choices in the most recent Fantastic Four movie/disaster, even if that movie was so fatally flawed). But I believe to a certain extent, any Superhero movie that succeeded in the world of audiences and critics, has followed a similar formula; a certain flavor sprinkled throughout that makes it universally accessible. Have a linear story to follow. Focus on only a few central plots. Throw in some easter eggs for the die-hard fans. And levity. Lots of levity. Even in the aftermath of the world literally crashing down around our heroes, they're in the mood for shawarma. Key to success: Have. Plenty. Of. Levity.
</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<section class=" review-sec3">
<div class="container">
<div class="row">

<div class="col-sm-12">

<p>Batman v Superman breaks pretty much all these rules. It's story is non-linear, jumping without warning between the past and the present, dreams and reality. It juggles a multitude of plots varying in size and significance. It's stuffed full of nods to comic fans, that left most general audiences scratching their heads.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-sm-6">
<p>And as for levity... well, I suppose Lex Luthor was a little comedic? No? Maybe? No?</p>
</div>
<div class="col-sm-6">
<img src="assets/img/funnylex.gif" class="img-responsive" />
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>


<section class="container-fluid" id="points">
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-12 text-center">
<div class="container">
<div class="row point" id="characters" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
<div class="col-sm-12 col-md-6 col-lg-7">
<h2>Characters</h2>
<p>The characters felt mature and had depth. Everyone seemed to be haunted by something. Batman, with the loss of his parents, his morals, his hope. Superman, with the consequences and guilt of his attempts at heroism. Lex Luthor, with the psychological trauma caused by his father and the cynicism of God and power. Wonder Woman, with the loss of her faith in the good of humanity. Even the ordinary people of society were dealing with the aftermath of the events of Man of Steel, and divisive views of Superman. So much personal baggage was woven throughout this movie; some blatantly obvious (Bruce Wayne haunted by his parent's death), some merely hinted at in snatches of dialogue (Lex offhandedly referencing his difficult childhood with his father). Everyone felt real, especially mankind's polarizing response to Superman's presence. Let's be real, if a superhuman alien showed up in our world today, a good portion of the population would respond with suspicion and fear, and they would be justified in doing so. Despite all the mythic grandeur of this movie, the people it depicted felt surprisingly grounded.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-sm-12 col-md-6 col-lg-5">
<div class="point-img">
<div id="char-superman" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the top after 0.2s"><img src="assets/img/character-superman.png" class="img-responsive" />
</div>

<div id="char-wonderwoman" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 0.2s"><img src="assets/img/character-wonderwoman.png" class="img-responsive" />
<div id="char-batman" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.2s"><img src="assets/img/character-batman.png" class="img-responsive" />
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="row point" id="action" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
<div class="col-sm-12 col-md-6 col-lg-7 pull-right">
<h2>Action</h2>
<p>The action was like watching motion art. Brutal fight scenes were difficult to watch but at the same time transfixing in their sheer fluidity and beauty. Each battle had its own visual style that captured the atmosphere of the situation. Batman's fight with two dozen thugs felt tight and up-close to the camera, brutal to the point that we could feel the pain of each punch. The namesake fight between Superman and Batman was more spread out over various environments and surroundings as the heroes pushed and threw each other around with furiosity. The final battle with Doomsday was the very definition of epic with each hero bringing their own fighting style and skills to the match. It was nothing short of gleeful to see Wonder Woman take the lead in aggressively attacking Doomsday and showing her prowess as a centuries-old warrior.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-sm-12 col-md-6 col-lg-5 point-img">
<img src="assets/img/underfoot.jpg" class="img-responsive" />
</div>

</div>

</div>

</div>
</div>

<div class="row point" id="story">
<div class="overlay"></div>
<div class="col-sm-12" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
<h2>Story</h2>
<p>But what captivated me most about BvS, was the story arc of the characters. Especially the main two. Batman started as a jaded, wasted, shell of a man, brutally branding the criminals he apprehends, and outright refusing to see any good in the world around him, most specifically in Superman. Superman for his part was struggling with the increasing doubt as to his true purpose on earth, even as he felt the weight of guilt for his actions. He was torn between the responsibility of protecting the world around him while also protecting the only family he has left on this planet, the two women he loves; Martha Kent and Lois Lane.</p>
<p>While Batman and Superman were pitched as visual juxtapositions of each other, Day vs Night, the metaphor runs deeper. Batman is devoid of hope. Superman is the very embodiment of hope.</p>

<p>Batman only sees darkness in people, so he is blinded to the goodness of Superman. Superman on the other hand, is so willing to believe the best in people, that he fails to see the threat in them. This was masterfully captured in the senate explosion scene. The look of utter defeat and shame on Superman's face in the immediate aftermath of the explosion, showed his realization that his naive optimism had been his biggest hindrance. But by the end, Superman succeeds in being the ultimate beacon of light and hope, awakening hope in the dark shadows of Batman's life. The change in Batman from the beginning of the movie to the end is palpable. And that is perhaps Superman's greatest achievement in a movie titled Batman v Superman.</p>
</div>

<!--<div class="col-sm-12 col-md-6 col-lg-5 point-img" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
SENATE EXPLOSION AFTERMATH IMAGE 
</div>-->
</div>

<div class="container">
<div class="row point" id="performances">
<div class="col-sm-12">
<h2>Performances</h2>
</div>
<div class="col-sm-6" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
<p>The acting in this movie was spectacular. Henry Cavill was brilliant as a layered and conflicted Superman that for once, we could all relate to. Ben Affleck shined as a beaten and brutal Batman. And Gal Gadot, while having minimal screen time, electrified every scene she was in.</p>

<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-12">
<p>On a personal note, it felt amazing to see a woman in a superhero movie depicted with such grace, beauty and power, without being relegated to eye-candy and objectification to please the teenage fanboys. (ahem... Black Widow).
</p>
</div>
<div class="col-sm-12">
<img src="assets/img/galgadot.jpg" class="img-responsive" />
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="col-sm-6">
<img src="assets/img/clark.jpg" class="img-responsive" />
<img src="assets/img/bruce.jpg" class="img-responsive" />
</div>
</div>


<div class="row point" id="others">
<div class="col-sm-12">
<h3>Other points of interest</h3>


<div class="row list">
<div class="col-sm-4"><h4>Visuals</h4> Zack Snyder's knack for creating breathtaking visuals is evidenced throughout the movie. An exorbitant amount of attention to detail shines through, and scenes are shot in exciting perspectives and angles. There's are also heavy religious references throughout the movie; Superman obviously being a Christ-like figure. I noticed this especially in the scene where Superman's dead body is carefully handed down from a height by Batman to Wonder Woman, and is transferred to the lap of a weeping Lois Lane. It visually played out similarly to the Biblical moment when Jesus' body is brought down from the cross and lain in his mother Mary's lap. Powerful and captivating imagery.</div>
<div class="col-sm-4"><h4>Plot Twists</h4> Warner Bros. kind of screwed up by revealing too much of the movie's main beats in pre-release trailers. However, there were still a few moments in the movie that hit me out of nowhere. The explosion at the Senate for one (Granny's Peach Tea, anyone?). But in a much bigger way, the death of Superman at the end was completely unexpected and a bold move to make. Call Zack Snyder what you like, but a predictable storyteller he most certainly is not.
</div>
<div class="col-sm-4"><h4>Score</h4> Hanz Zimmer and Junkie XL have crafted a masterpiece of a score which truly becomes its own character in the movie. It was good to hear the epic and moving Superman theme from Man of Steel reprised, and Lex Luthor's theme expertly conveys the character's intrigue and overall creepiness. If there was such a thing as the quintessential comic supervillain theme, this would be it. But the standout track is without a doubt the Wonder Woman theme. I challenge anyone to listen to it and not feel like they could muster up the energy to break down a door; it's the definition of kick-ass.</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

</div>


</section>

<section id="summary">
<div class="overlay">
<div class="container">
<div class="row text-center">
<div class="col-lg-8 col-lg-offset-2 col-md-8 col-md-offset-2 col-sm-10 col-sm-offset-1">
<h4 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.4s">
<p>In all honesty, it is mildly exhausting to watch BvS. Because it isn't a relaxing movie. It will not let its audience settle into any sort of comfort zone. Above all, it makes you think. And some people may not enjoy that in a superhero genre movie. And that's fair. But personally, it was refreshing to not have everything spelt out for me, and to have to infer the motivations and histories of characters. Yes BvS was exhausting, but it was exhausting like a great work-out that leaves you tired but energized. If there's one hallmark of Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice, it was that it was different, but the thing is... I loved that about it.</p>
</h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

</section>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>BvS could be awesome</title>
	  <link>/thethingis//bvs-could-be-awesome</link>
	  <author>Samanalie Dias Jayasinha</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-02-12T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/thethingis//bvs-could-be-awesome</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <!--HEADER SECTION END-->

<section class="container-fluid intro">
<div class="row">
<div class="col-lg-4 col-lg-offset-4 col-md-8 col-md-offset-2 col-sm-10 col-sm-offset-1">

<p data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
Exaggeration and hyperbole aside, I can safely say that Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice is my most anticipated movie event of 2016. It's hard to believe that it's finally here. Early reviews are leaking through the sieve of Social Media, and everyone seems severely polarized on the topic. The Critics and Fans seem to be having their own showdown in terms of opinions on this movie. I am yet to see it, so this is purely based on my own opinion and speculation of the promotional material released for BvS. This is why I think it has the potential to rock...</p>
</div>
</div>

</section>


<section class="price-sec text-center container-fluid" id="showdown">

<div class="row">

<div class="col-lg-6  col-md-6 col-xs-6 bat" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.1s">
<div class="overlay"></div>

<h1>Batman</h1>
<ul class="showdown-list" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.4s">
<li>Superior deduction skills</li>
<li>Master strategist</li>
<li>Expert martial artist</li>
<li>Advanced technology</li>
<li>Willing to fight dirty</li>
<li class="weakness">Weakness: Mortality</li>
</ul>

</div>
<div class="col-lg-6  col-md-6 col-xs-6 sup" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 0.2s">
<div class="overlay"></div>

<h1>Superman</h1>
<ul class="showdown-list" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 0.4s">
<li>Superhuman strength</li>
<li>Ability of Flight</li>
<li>Heat Vision</li>
<li>Invulnerable in most conditions</li>
<li class="weakness">Weakness: Kryptonite, Inexperiance</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>

</section>
<!--PRICING SECTION END-->


<section class="container" id="points">
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-12 text-center">
<h1>Things I'm looking forward to:</h1>

<div class="row point" id="batfleck" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
<div class="col-sm-12 col-md-6 col-lg-7">
<h2>01. Batfleck</h2>
<p>Despite what the rest of the internet has to say on the subject, I've always been a fan of Ben Affleck. I forgive him for the J-Lo phase (we all make mistakes), and he has certainly come a long way since 2003's Daredevil.</p> <p>Against all odds, and a bevy of naysayers, everyone seems to agree, this just might be the greatest movie incarnation of Batman we have ever seen. Utterly menacing and brutally bad-ass, this is the first Batman that I truly fear, and I mean that in a good way. I mean seriously, would you want to run into this guy in a dark alley? <span class="shudder"> ~ Shudder ~ </span></p>
</div>
<div class="col-sm-12 col-md-6 col-lg-5 point-img">
<img src="assets/img/BatmanReveal.gif" class="img-responsive"/>
</div>
</div>
<div class="row point" id="wonderwoman" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
<div class="col-sm-12 col-md-6 col-lg-7 pull-right">
<h2>02. Gal Gadot's Wonder Woman</h2>
<p>Another casting choice that set the internet on fire, but she's sure done a 180, with early reviews hailing her as the best part of the movie, especially considering that she probably has a miniscule amount of screen time in comparison to her male superhero counterparts. I could write an entire article on why I think her casting alone is an important step forward for Hollywood, but I'll hold off on that till I've seen the movie. But rest assured, from what I've seen and heard so far, this woman is both beauty and beast in the best way possible.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-sm-12 col-md-6 col-lg-5 point-img">
<img src="assets/img/Wonder-Woman-shield.jpg" class="img-responsive"/>
</div>

</div>
<div class="row point" id="superconflict" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
<div class="col-sm-12 col-md-6 col-lg-7">
<h2>03. Conflicted Superman</h2>
<p>
If I had to choose one thing that I liked about Man of Steel, I would say Henry Cavill. If I had to choose two, then the other would be that the Superman of that movie was more humanized than anything I had seen before. He made mistakes, he ran away from his powers, and he had realistic human parents who mentored him in exactly the way we would expect our parents to treat us if we suddenly manifested superhuman strength; with protective caution. The world is a scary place, and humans tend to be the worst thing about it, so it makes sense for Superman, as an outsider, to be weary and conflicted about how he goes about things. BvS is poised to bring us more depth in that aspect. 
</p>
</div>
<div class="col-sm-12 col-md-6 col-lg-5 point-img" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
<img src="assets/img/supermanKent.jpg" class="img-responsive"/>
</div>
</div>
<div class="row point" id="lex">
<div class="col-sm-12">
<h2>04. The Lex Luthor of today</h2>
<img src="assets/img/lex.jpg" class="img-responsive"/>
<p>
It seems like almost every casting decision in this movie has been met with trepidation, and Jesse Eisenberg as Lex Luthor is one that still hasn't proven itself to be bankable. But from what they've given us so far, it seems like this incarnation of the billionaire mastermind is moulded after what most modern billionaires look like today. Young, casual, socially awkward, unassuming enough that we would trust them with vast amounts of our personal information… remind you of anyone? (Zucker…cough). And if that's the case, then who better to play this new Luthor than the very actor who is renowned for portraying one of the real-life billionaire masterminds of our generation.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="row point" id="action" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
<div class="col-sm-12">
<h2>05. Action Action Action</h2>
<p>
Say what you want about Zach Snyder, but the man knows how to give us great action scenes. And from that Batman trailer sequence alone (you already know what I'm referring to, because yes it was that good), I think it's safe to expect beautiful and brutal action, which is what Zach Snyder excels at capturing (for evidence, see: 300).
</p>
<div class="fight">
<img src="assets/img/BatmanFight.gif" class="img-responsive"/>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="row point" id="story" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
<div class="col-sm-12">
<h2>06. Story, story, story</h2>
<p>BvS is setting up to tackle some heady issues.</p>
<img src="assets/img/supersoldiers.jpg" class="img-responsive"/>
<div class="wr-issues">
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-3 issue" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.4s"><span>Balance of power</span></div>
<div class="col-sm-3 issue" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.4s"><span>The consequences of conflict</span></div>
<div class="col-sm-3 issue" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 0.7s"><span>Media bias</span></div>
<div class="col-sm-3 issue" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 0.7s"><span>Government suspicion</span></div>
</div>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-3 issue" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.4s"><span>Corruption of justice</span></div>
<div class="col-sm-3 issue" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the left after 0.4s"><span>Prejudice</span></div>
<div class="col-sm-3 issue" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 0.7s"><span>Conspiracy theories</span></div>
<div class="col-sm-3 issue" data-scroll-reveal="enter from the right after 0.7s"><span>Faith in humanity as a whole</span></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>
...just to name a few. Just to be clear, this movie has a flying alien, glowing meteorites, a genetic hybrid monster, and a grown man dressed as a bat. Throwing these real world topics into the mix is what will make the movie worth investing in emotionally.
</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>



<section class="testi-sec">
<div class="overlay">
<div class="container">
<div class="row text-center">
<div class="col-lg-8 col-lg-offset-2 col-md-8 col-md-offset-2 col-sm-10 col-sm-offset-1">
<h4 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.8s">
<p>

Are there things that I'm anxious about regarding this movie? Sure. Trying to avoid critic reviews is like holding your breath; you can only do it for so long. Will this be a perfect movie? Highly unlikely. But the thing is, this is Batman v Superman; childhood heroes battling it out on the big-screen like we've never seen them before. Sure there might be things to gripe about. But I don't want to gripe. I don't want to fight. Let's leave that to Bats and Supes.</p> <p>So I'm setting aside my expectations, and I'm just strapping in for the ride. Just bring it on BvS… I am so ready.</p>

</h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

</section>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
