<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>summernalie.github.io/thethingis/</title>
   
   <link>http://www.samanalie.com/thethingis/</link>
   <description>Thoughts on Movies, Books and TV</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> Samanalie Dias Jayasinha</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Musings of a Metropolis Victim: Part 2</title>
	  <link>/thethingis//musings-metropolis-2</link>
	  <author>Samanalie Dias Jayasinha</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-06-12T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/thethingis//musings-metropolis-2</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div class="container"> 
  <h1 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
    Part 2: Musings of a Metropolis Victim
</h1> 
</div>
  <img src="assets/img/hospital.jpg"/>
<div class="container">                    

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-sm-12">
<section class="article-content">

    <p>I sat on the edge of the cliff, ready to jump. I balled my fingers into a fist and clenched my teeth. Even if it meant a whole lot of pain, I was ready. This was my only chance. With all my might, I heaved myself forward, propelling my body to leap off the precipice and into the vast unknown below me…
</p>
    
    <p>...</p>
    
    <p>Except that the edge of the cliff was the edge of a bed… Except that the deep chasm beneath me was a two-foot drop down to cold ceramic tiles… Except that, crushed in my clenched fists was the crisp white cotton of the bed-sheet. Except that, although I had pushed my body forward with every-ounce of willpower that I could muster, I hadn't done anything more than utter a muffled grunt and slide forward half an inch on the bed. 
</p>
    
    <p>I was frozen. No matter how hard I tried, I couldn't get my legs to obey. The lower half of my body felt like concrete, and somehow the rest of my body had decided it would be better to behave similarly. I looked down at my right leg, mummified neatly in yards of bandages, and I could see that a tiny dot of red had appeared on the side where my ankle would be. <em>Great. Just what I need. More blood.</em> </p>
    
    <p>I knew my leg wouldn't take any weight, even if I had managed to get off of the bed. I knew I would have instantly crumpled to the ground like a rag-doll. But at least crawling would have been an option. Even if I had to drag my body across the icy floor, there was a chance I could make it to the door. <em>The door is locked, idiot.</em> Yeah, I knew it was locked, but it was literally the only way in and out of this 8-by-12-foot pristine prison cell that had been my home ever since I had woken up. I didn't even know how long I had been here, because I had no idea how long I had been unconscious. The last thing I remembered before this room, was being trapped in the debris that was once Metropolis; breathing in the smell of dirt and concrete as the world around me grew darker; waiting to die.
</p>
    
    <p>Yes I knew the door was locked… but I had to try. Maybe by some unimaginable miracle they had left it open, just this once.</p>
    
    <p><em>And then, what? Crawl your way to freedom?</em> I didn't know what would come next. All I knew is I had to get out of this room. </p>
    
    <p>I heard footsteps approaching from afar, growing louder with each step. My time was up. My window of opportunity had slipped away. Whatever they had injected into me was doing its job. My lower-body was completely unresponsive. I wasn't going anywhere. I slumped backwards against the pillows at the head of the bed. I didn't even bother trying to drag my dead-weight legs back up onto the mattress. They would do it for me when they came in. The little red dot of blood was now a patch the size of my palm. The only thing I had succeeded to do was make myself bleed more. </p>
    
    <p>They would know what I had tried to do. And it wouldn't matter to them. There wouldn't even be any repercussions for my pathetic attempt at escape. They knew I wouldn't be getting out of here on my own. </p>
    
    <p>I settled back into the crushing embrace of despair, as the door opened.</p>
    
    
</section>
        </div>
</div>
</div>


  
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Musings of a Metropolis Victim: Part 1</title>
	  <link>/thethingis//musings-metropolis-1</link>
	  <author>Samanalie Dias Jayasinha</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-05-12T00:00:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/thethingis//musings-metropolis-1</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div class="container"> 
  <h1 data-scroll-reveal="enter from the bottom after 0.2s">
    Part 1: Musings of a Metropolis Victim
</h1> 
</div>
  <img src="assets/img/metropolis.png"/>
<div class="container">                    

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-sm-12">
<section class="article-content">

    <p>This is it. This is exactly how and where I’m going to die. Trapped under 2 tons of concrete. My right leg skewered by 12 foot long rebar. Unable to move. Throat hoarse from yelling for help. Slowly suffocating in the dust and smoke. Bleeding out. Alone.</p>
    
    <p>No one can hear me. I’ve been screaming for what feels like hours. Nobody is coming to get me, ‘cos nobody knows where I am. And frankly, nobody cares. I’m alone in a city where nobody knows me, and every single person here is probably running for their lives right now. That’s what I was doing too, before. Before I tripped. Before a dozen people trampled me in the stampede to get out of the alley. Before I saw a bright flash of red light tear through the building on my left, and I heard that sickening sizzling sound. The sound I’d heard moments ago when the red beams tore through a building a distance away. The sound had been faint before, but this time it buzzed loudly in my ears, setting my teeth on edge. I could almost feel it vibrating my skull. And with that sound, the red beams; slicing through concrete and metal as if they were butter. The last thing I saw was slabs of what used to be the building wall, come tumbling towards me, and then blinding pain in my right leg, and then darkness.</p>
    
    <p>I’m awake now, so I can fully appreciate the searing pain of having a 4 inch thick, half-rusted metal rod piercing through my ankle. Actually that’s a lie. It was about half a minute right after I woke up; the moment I unthinkingly tried to move my leg that I really felt the peak of the pain. It’s faded into a dull throbbing ache, since I learned to lie still and not disturb my leg. I had to learn that, unless I wanted to pass out again.</p>
    
    <p>There was a shard of glass stuck in my cheek, but it dislodged while I was yelling. Now there’s just blood. Blood, a hole in my cheek and more pain. But bearable pain in comparison to my leg. The slabs of concrete wall had miraculously piled on each other at such an angle that they created a small pocket of space around me. Did I say miraculous? I meant to say, like some sick cosmic joke. ‘Cos instead of crushing me instantly and that being the end of it, I get to sit in a pool of my own blood and slowly watch the world go dark around me.</p>
    
    <p>I can’t hear much except for what sounds like distant booms. I don’t know what those could be. More buildings coming down? Or maybe something else… The funny thing is, I can’t hear any screams. When it all started, there were screams everywhere. Everyone was on the street looking up at that monstrous thing, sitting in the sky right over the city, like some colossal spidery monster with long thin limbs poised high over the tallest building in Metropolis. And then the resounding boom, that made the ground beneath us tremble. The woman standing near me in the street had screamed first. And then it seemed like everyone was screaming all at once.</p>
    
    <p>The pool of blood collecting around my leg is sizeable now. My leg actually doesn’t hurt so bad anymore. Is this what dying feels like?</p>
    
    <p>I don’t remember why exactly I had started running. I didn’t even know what I was running from or to. It was just what everyone around me was doing, so I followed in the panic. I didn’t know where I was going. I was just a week into my work-assignment in Metropolis, and I still had no idea which street led where. So I just ran. I remember looking back for a moment up at the sky, and seeing fire raining down. And I could have sworn there was something else. Two shapes, one black and one red, hurtling through the air in the midst of fiery debris.</p>
    
    <p>Who are they? Did they cause this? Are there more of them? What was that ship doing here? What the hell was going on? …One thing’s for sure, I am never going to find out. I am going to suffocate in this dark hole of concrete and death. Alone. And maybe that’s a good thing. Maybe everyone in the city is dead. Maybe that’s why I can’t hear any screams anymore. Maybe it’s better that I die in here, than out there. Maybe they killed everyone in the city.</p>
    
    <p>What if they find me? Would they help me? Would they destroy me like they destroyed the city? I don’t know. And I’ll never know. ‘Cos this is it. This is how and where I’m going to die.</p>
    
    
</section>
        </div>
</div>
</div>


  
	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
